欢迎大家回来，这是聚和态物理的二十一讲
welcome back everyone this is the
twenty-first lecture of the condensed
当我们上次离开时​​，我们谈论的是
matter course when we left off last time
we were talking about magnetism in
特别是我们在谈论铁磁性
particular we were talking about Ferro
magnetism Ferro magnetism and everything
我们所说的关于磁性的重点实际上是理解
that we said about magnetism was really
focused on understanding what happens at
零温度所有时刻彼此对齐，但通常
zero temperature all of the moments
aligning with each other but generally
您可以问一个问题，当您抬高铁磁磁铁时会发生什么
you can ask the question what happens to
a Ferro magnet as you raise the
温度，我们对费罗发生的事情有一些直觉
temperature and we have a little bit of
an intuition about what happens in Ferro
有限T的磁性将是您今天的大部分演讲的主题
magnetism at finite T which will be the
subject of much of today's lecture you
知道在零温度下所有时刻都对齐，但是当您打开
know at zero temperature all the moments
align but then when you turn on the
温度会有一些热波动和瞬间
temperature there's going to be some
thermal fluctuations and the moments
将不再完全对齐，在某些时候我们可能没有费罗
won't be completely aligned anymore and
at some point we might not have Ferro
磁性，所以总的来说，我们想知道的是
magnetism at all so in general what we
want to know is we'd like to know as a
温度的函数什么是磁化强度
function of temperature what is the
magnetization some sort of equation of
状态，也许我们也将允许外部施加磁场
state and maybe we'll also allow for an
externally applied magnetic field so
这就是我们有兴趣发现的内容，我应该先介绍一下
this is what we're interested in finding
out now I should start with a bit of a
请注意，在上一讲中，我们花了很多时间思考
caveat in the last lecture we spent a
lot of time thinking about the idea of
由于长距离偶极相互作用而产生的磁畴和
magnetic domains which are created due
to long-range dipolar interactions and
即使本地物理学是要对齐铁磁磁体中的所有矩
even though the local physics is to
align all the moments in a Ferro magnet
在低温下会有一些全球物理学
at low temperature there will be some
global physics which will make some
区域朝上，某些区域朝下，以最小化全局磁场
regions point up in some regions point
down to minimize the global magnetic
能量，所以我们今天不打算考虑那种物理学
energy so we're not going to think about
that kind of physics today we're only
会局部地思考，所以对我们来说，零温度的铁磁体会
going to think sort of locally so for us
a Ferro magnet at zero temperature would
至少为了今天的目的使他们的所有时刻保持一致，然后我们
have all their moments aligned at least
for for the purpose of today and then we
如果我们感兴趣的话，可以稍后再进行远距离的偶极相互作用
can put back in the long range dipolar
interactions later if we're interested
所以我们将使用一个非常简单的模型来尝试了解发生了什么
so we're going to use a very simple
model to try to understand what happens
到有限温度下的磁化强度，我们使用自旋1/2缓和
to the magnetization at finite
temperature we use the spin 1/2 easing
通过旋转1/2缓和模型1/2缓和我们的意思是每个站点上的旋转
model 1/2 easing by spin 1/2 easing what
we mean is that the spin on each site
将是一些Sigma I指向Z方向，其中Sigma I等于加号或
will be some Sigma I pointing the Z
direction where Sigma I equals plus or
减1/2，我们将写之前见过的哈密顿量
minus 1/2 and we'll write the
Hamiltonian which we've seen before
所有部位的总和将与外部磁场耦合
there will be a coupling to the external
magnetic field the sum over all sites
Sigma I和这里我将外部磁场放在Z方向上
Sigma I and here I've put the external
magnetic field in the Z direction and
那么我们将相邻自旋之间的耦合减去1/2 J总和
then we have the coupling between
neighbor spins minus 1/2 J sum over
相邻的旋转I和J Sigma I Sigma J，所以括号表示法也是
neighboring spins I and J Sigma I Sigma
J so again the bracket notation means
我和J是邻居，在这里我们关心的是铁磁体，所以我们
that I and J are neighbors and here
we're concerned with a ferromagnet so we
将J设置为大于零好吧，这就是缓动模型
set J greater than zero alright so this
is the easing model a fairly simple
模型写下来，但正如我之前提到的，实际上很难
model to write down but as I mentioned
before it's actually quite difficult to
解决它在一维可解决的二维问题
solve it is solvable in one dimension in
two dimensions it's solvable without the
磁场，除此之外，它根本无法解决，这意味着我们
magnetic field and beyond that it's not
solvable at all so that means we're
将不得不诉诸某种近似方法来获得某种
going to have to resort to some sort of
approximation method to get some sort of
了解磁化缓动模型的有限状态
understanding of what happens to the
magnetization the easing model at finite
现在有很多可以使用的近似方法，但是
temperature now there's lots of
approximation methods one can use but
理论家的首选或流氓的首选是
the first resort of theorists or first
resort of scoundrels is what's known as
平均场理论平均场理论，我们将使用它来尝试
mean field theory mean field theory
which we're going to use to try to
估计在有限温度下哈密顿量会发生什么
estimate what happens to this
Hamiltonian at finite temperature so
平均场理论可以近似定义为：
mean field theory can be approximately
defined as whenever you approximate some
运算符或数量
operator or quantity some operator or
quantity with an expectation with an
平均或均值
average or a mean
这不仅在凝聚态物理中非常普遍
and this is used very very commonly not
only in condensed matter physics but
也在凝聚态物理之外，这是一个非常普遍的
also outside of condensed matter physics
and this is sort of a very general
语句，所以有很多事情可以作为一个近似值开始
statement so there are many things that
you can start approximating as a
期望值是平均值，因此我们将使用特定的
expectation are an average so we're
going to use a particular variety of
平均场理论被称为分子场理论或也被称为
mean field theory known as molecular
field theory theory or also it's known
作为副均场理论副均场理论MFT这是同一个人
as vice mean field theory vice mean
field theory MFT this is the same guy
副教授，他发现了磁铁中的畴的概念，并讨论了他
vice who was discovered the idea of
domains in magnets as well discussed him
上次，我不得不承认我不知道是在E之前还是在E之前
last time and I have to admit I don't
know if it's I before E or E before I
抱歉，我的拼写不是很好，所以
there so apologize about that my
spelling is not very good so the idea of
分子场论它基本上有两个非常简单的步骤，您可以
molecular field theory it has basically
two very simple steps that you can
始终遵循第一步是您应该对待系统的一部分
always follow step one is that you
should treat one piece of the system
确切地说，您隔离了系统的一小部分，它可能是一个单元
exactly you isolate one little piece of
the system it might be a single unit
单元格，或者它可能只是一个站点，您将要对其进行精确处理
cell or it might be just a single site
and you're going to treat that exactly
所以精确地对待一个系统正确地对待一个系统
so treat one piece of system exactly
treat one piece of system exactly
其他所有的东西都应该平均，所以我们实际上已经看到
everything else should be averaged all
else is averaged so we've actually seen
在我们研究固体的爱因斯坦模型之前
something like this before when we study
the Einstein model of the solid we
正确地处理了一个原子，我们正确地将其视为量子力学，但是我们
treated one atom exactly we treated as
quantum mechanics correctly but we
将所有其他原子的电势平均化，使之变得粗糙
average the potential from all the other
atoms we sort of made it into some rough
平均，一个原子刚好成为这个近似势
average and it just became this
approximate potential well that one atom
即使是非常粗略的近似，也存在一个原子
is living in so even though it was very
crude approximation is that one atom we
说实话，这是所有邻居的全部影响
treated very honestly it was all the
effect of all the neighbors that we
近似维塞处理手段的第二步理论
approximated the second step of vyse
means to deal theory
第二步是自洽自洽
step two is self-consistency
self-consistency
这意味着所有作品的所有作品都应该相同，并且在
which means all pieces all pieces should
be the same should look the same in the
末尾应该看起来一样，所以不管是哪一部分
end should look same at the end and so
it shouldn't matter which part of the
我们专注于对整个系统进行精确处理的系统
system we focus on to treat exactly at
the end of the day the whole system
应该再次看起来均匀，关于一件应该没什么特别的
should look homogeneous again shouldn't
be anything special about the one piece
我们要看一下，对我们来说，我们要对待宽松政策
we're going to look at so for us we're
going to we're going to treat the easing
铁磁体，我们将只关注一个站点中的一个单元电池
ferromagnet and we're going to focus in
on just one site a one unit cell in this
如果缓动铁磁体的晶胞是一个单一的站点，那么我们
case the easing ferromagnet the unit
cell is a single site so the we so we
专注于好，所以第一步看一个站点看一个站点我
focus on okay so step one look at one
site look at one site site I for the
缓和铁磁体我只为站点写下哈密顿量
easing ferromagnet I'll write down the
Hamiltonian for site I only so
站点I的哈密顿量是GμBB乘以Sigma I，即与
Hamiltonian for site I is G mu B B times
Sigma I that's the coupling to the
外部施加的磁场，然后将耦合到所有
externally applied magnetic field then
there's going to be the coupling to all
杰伊（Jay）是我的邻居I I Sigma J
of its neighbors which I'll write this
this way jay is neighbor of i I Sigma J
然后乘上西格玛一世，所以我写出了哈密顿量的所有术语
and then times Sigma I so I've written
out all the terms in the Hamiltonian
包含自旋Sigma I的代码现在您可能已经在这里想了一秒钟
that contain the spin Sigma I right now
you may have thought here for a second
我可能会降低写在上面的1/2的因数，但我没有
that I may have dropped the factor of
1/2 that's written up top but I haven't
然后记住顶部的1/2的因数在那里，因为
then remember that the factor of 1/2 of
top is there because in that sum
严格来说，有Sigma 1 Sigma 2但也有Sigma 2 Sigma 1
strictly speaking there's Sigma 1 Sigma
2 but there's also Sigma 2 Sigma 1 in
如果Sigma I是Sigma 1，那么这个总和不会反过来发生
this sum if Sigma I is Sigma 1 it
doesn't occur the other way around it
仅发生一次，因此Sigma 2 Sigma 1在此仅代表一次
only occurs once so Sigma 2 Sigma 1
would just be represented once in this
哈密​​顿量，这样写时就不需要1/2的因数
Hamiltonian so you don't need the factor
of 1/2 when you write it this way all
对，所以看起来有点复杂，让我们看看是否可以简化一下
right so this looks a little complicated
let's see if we can simplify it a little
位将写入将定义定义有效磁场是有效的
bit will write will define define an
effective magnetic field be effective be
通过以下方程式有效
effective via the following equation G
mu B
有效等于GM是外部磁场的实际磁场或
be effective equals GM you be the actual
magnetic field the external plus or
减去邻居J的影响乘以小J的总和是的邻居
minus the influence of the neighbors J
times sum over small J is a neighbor of
我是Sigma J的成员，所以我们正在做的是
I of I Sigma J so what we're doing is
we're wrapping up the interaction with
邻居，我们称它为有效磁场的一部分
the neighbors and we're calling it part
of the effective magnetic field okay in
我们可以将站点I的哈密顿量重写为G
terms of this quantity we can rewrite
the Hamiltonian for site I as just G
可能是有效时间Sigma I，它看起来非常简单
maybe be effective times Sigma I which
looks extremely simple it just looks
像单自旋Sigma I耦合到外部有效磁场
like a single spin Sigma I coupled to an
external effective magnetic field be
有效，我们知道如何解决，我们解决了之前
effective and we know how to solve that
we solved that before which is have a
磁场中的单自旋应该很容易吧，好吧
single spin in a magnetic field it
should be easy right well okay that's a
有点欺骗性，因为我们在这里撒谎是有效的，而不仅仅是
little deceptive because we've sort of
lied here be effective is not just a
这里的数字不是常数它实际上具有一定的自由度
number here it's not a constant it
actually has some degrees of freedom a
隐藏在其中，您应该将其视为具有所有这些Sigma J的运算符
hidden in it you should think of it as
an operator it has all these Sigma J's
它使生活变得复杂，这会使一切变得非常复杂，因此
in it and that complicates life is going
to make everything really complicated so
我们真的不能简单地将其视为与恒定磁场耦合的自旋
we can't really treat this simply as a
spin coupled to a constant magnetic
场好吧，这就是我的意思场论派上用场了
field okay so that's what I mean field
theory comes in handy the rule of mean
场论认为，除了这一点之外，您应该近似一切
field theory is that you should
approximate everything except this one
按照平均值旋转，因此第一步近似是有效的
spin in terms of an average so step one
step one is approximate be effective by
有效平均值的总和将是有效的
sum average of the effective average
would be effective okay by taking this
平均而不是运算符，现在只是一个数字，因此
average instead of being an operator
it's now just a number so the
哈密​​顿量成为系统一哈密顿量成为HI是G mu B
Hamiltonian becomes system one the
Hamiltonian becomes H I is G mu B
对有效的期望，现在只是一些
expectation of the effective which is
now just a number
耦合到Sigma I，而实际上只是一个自旋耦合到一个常数
coupled to Sigma I and that really is
just a single spin coupled to a constant
磁场，所以我们知道如何解决这个问题
magnetic field so we know how to solve
this we've done it before
我们做到了，您去年做到了，我们在上一讲中做到了，所以我只是
we did it you've done it last year we
did it in the last lecture so I'll just
写下第一步，写下分区函数
write down the first step you write down
the partition function its
您-βG mu B期望值，并且对我的有效x加上1/2加上e
you the - beta G mu B expectation and be
effective x plus 1/2 plus e to the my
G mu beta G me B期望有效倍数1/2
G mu beta G me B expectation be
effective times 1/2
我希望这看起来很熟悉，然后我们可以在
I hope this looks familiar then we can
differentiate this partition function in
为了获得对Sigma I的期望，然后对Sigma I的期望变为
order to get expectation of Sigma I and
the expectation of Sigma I then becomes
βG mu B期望的负1/2双曲正切值和有效时间
minus 1/2 hyperbolic tangent of beta G
mu B expectation and be effective times
1/2好，现在我们有了Sigma I的表达式
1/2 okay so now we have an expression
for Sigma I for the expectation of Sigma
I在外部有效磁场方面的温度和Gμ
I in terms of the external the effective
magnetic field the temperature and G mu
B到目前为止对这个好东西感到满意，所以现在
B so far so good
happy with this alright good so now the
最后一步是我们必须弄清楚有效的期望是什么
last step is we have to figure out what
this expectation of the effective is
好，这样期望就这样G mu B有效的期望就是G
okay so expectation right this way G mu
B expectation of the effective is just G
mu B是外部磁场减去J加上J的总和不是
mu B be the external magnetic field
minus J sum over J isn't is neighbor of
我对Sigma J的期望倍，所以我只取了
I of I times expectation of Sigma J okay
so I just took the average of of the
在这里有效，平均场理论的最后一步是最后
effective here and the the final step of
the mean field theory is that at the end
当天所有站点的外观应该相同，因此站点I的Sigma平均值
of the day all sites should look the
same so the average of Sigma on site I
应该与平均值相同，所以这是第二步自洽
should be the same as the average of so
this is step two self-consistency
I站点Sigma的平均值应与J站点的Sigma平均值相同
average of Sigma on site I should be the
same as the average of Sigma on site J
我和网站Jane的网站并没有什么特别之处，我们称之为
there's nothing special about site I
versus site Jane we'll just call it
西格玛好吧，所以我们只是将西格玛的平均值设置为每个
Sigma okay so we're just setting the
average of Sigma the same on every every
站点，所以如果我们这样做，那么我们的方程式就是
site so if we do that then our equation
here with the tange
双曲正切可以写成Sigma等于负1/2双曲
the hyperbolic tangent can be written as
Sigma equals minus 1/2 hyperbolic
切线，现在我将在有效的地方插入B的表达式
tangent and now I'll plug in our
expression for B effective where well
实际上好吧，好吧，我想这是一笔总和
actually all right well okay up here
this sum here I suppose
这里的和可以是Z乘以Sigma，其中Z是邻居的数量
this sum here it can be Z times Sigma
where Z is the number of neighbors sorry
自从我们将Sigma J的Sigma期望设置为正好是这个以来的邻居数量
number of neighbors since we set Sigma
expectation of Sigma J to be just this
数字Sigma，总和中有J个项，总和中有D个项很清楚
number Sigma and there's J terms in the
sum D terms in the sum is that clear
我只是对不起，有点混乱
what I just did
sorry it was a little messy okay all
对，所以最终结果是有形的减去beta JZ超过2倍
right so this ends up coming out
tangible minus beta J Z over 2 times
Sigma加beta G mu BB超过2，所以这只是对
Sigma plus beta G mu B B over 2 so this
is just a rewriting of this of the
我插入的双曲正切的等式在那里有效
equation up there with the hyperbolic
tangent I plugged in be effective and I
插入了J倍Z 4，其中我有J倍期望J倍Z倍Sigma
plugged in J times Z 4 where I had J
times expectation J times Z times Sigma
是我的J倍于邻居的总和乘以Sigma J的期望值的地方
is where I had J times sum over
neighbors times expectation of Sigma J
好是好好的好的好的好的，这是我们的最终结果
good yes good all right all right all
right so this is our our final result
这是Sigma幅度的某种自洽方程
and it's some sort of self-consistent
equation for the magnitude of Sigma
这是在站点I上旋转的期望，因此原则上我们现在有了
which is the expectation that's spin on
site I and so in principle we now have
我们针对Sigma的解决方案是耦合温度的函数
our solution for what Sigma is as a
function of the temperature the coupling
到邻居的数量邻居外部磁场的数量
to the neighbors the number of neighbors
external magnetic field okay it's a
复杂的方程式，但至少在原则上我们可以立即解决
complicated equation but at least in
principle we could solve it the moment
那么每个站点将减去GμB乘以Sigma，此处的标记就可以了
per site would then be minus G mu B
times Sigma where the sign so okay this
是每个自旋的时刻，负号来自电子
is the moment per for spin this minus
sign comes from the fact that electrons
带有负电荷，因此磁矩指向相反的方向
have negative charge so the magnetic
moment points in the opposite direction
的旋转，所以原则上我们现在已经解决了
of the spin
so in principle we've now solved our
问题，但这是一个复杂的先验方程，
problem however this is sort of a
complicated transcendental equation and
它的解决方案不是很明显，我们已经看到了Sigma的一些方程式，所以我们
it's not so obvious what its solution is
we've seen some equation for Sigma so we
必须弄清楚如何解决它，让我们先简化为一个简单的案例
have to figure out how to solve it and
let's simplify to a easy case first so
情况情况1r只是将情况设为零，外部磁场为0
case case 1r just set the case to be
equal zero external magnetic field is 0
在这种情况下，简化这个方程式，使符号向内移动，我们得到的Sigma为1/2
in which case simplifying this equation
moving a sign inside we get Sigma is 1/2
βJZ Sigma超过2的双曲正切值对
hyperbolic tangent of beta J Z Sigma
over 2 good still a hard equation to
解决，因为它仍然是Sigma的超越方程，但
solve because it's still a
transcendental equation for Sigma but
有一个很好的图形方法可以解决这个方程，即绘制y等于
there's a nice graphical way to solve
this equation which is to plot y equals
Sigma和y等于在同一图上的2上超过2的1/2 tange beta JZ Sigma
Sigma and y equals 1/2 tange beta J Z
Sigma over 2 on the same plot and where
他们相交是这个方程的解好，所以这就是我们要
they intersect is the solution of this
equation ok so that's what we're gonna
这样做就是我们要解决这个问题的方式，每个人都还在我身边
do that's how we're going to solve this
equation is everyone still with me
任何人都可以，是的，所以很好，所以我们首先要决定并移交
anyone happy yeah ok good so so here we
go first we have to decide and put over
这里好吧，我们在这里Y西格玛在这里啊温度西格玛吧
here ok let's all right here Y Sigma
over here ah temperature Sigma right
Sigma在这里，然后我们绘制第一个曲线y等于Sigma
Sigma over here then we'll plot the
first curve which is y equals Sigma like
这个y等于Sigma ok，这是我们要绘制的第一条曲线，然后
this y equals Sigma ok that's the first
curve that we want to plot and then the
第二条曲线是该双曲正切，渐近于1/2和负1/2
second curve is this hyperbolic tangent
which asymptotes at 1/2 and at minus 1/2
所以我们在这里渐近动物渐近线但是有两个
so we'll asymptote here animal
asymptotes down here but there's two
夸张哎呀这个图看起来是什么样的可能性
possibilities as to what this plot looks
like with the hyperbole oops and
双曲正切双曲正切看起来像什么
hyperbolic hyperbolic tangent what this
hyperbolic tangent looks like one
可能是低温发生什么情况低温
没开抱歉先做高温高温高温
not open sorry let's do high temperature
first high temperature high temperature
是第一种可能性，因此在高温下β很小，因此棕褐色
is the first possibility so in high
temperature beta is small and so the tan
CH是一个非常柔和的功能，因此看起来像这样，所以这是
CH is a very gentle function so it looks
kind of like this okay so this is the
低温高温
low high temperature high temperature
好人对此感到满意，那就是双曲线正切曲线
good people happy with that that's a
hyperbolic tangent curve and it
渐近线到这条虚线，所以我们看到的是这两条曲线
asymptotes to this dotted line so what
we see is these two curves the
双曲正切且y等于Sigma曲线仅在一个点处相交
hyperbolic tangent and the y equals
Sigma curve intersect only at one point
Sigma等于0，所以唯一的唯一解决方案是Sigma等于
at Sigma equals zero so the only
solution only solution is Sigma equals
零，这告诉我们您在高温下没有铁磁性
zero and that tells us that you don't
have ferromagnetism in high temperature
实际上，您得到的M等于磁化强度等于零或顺磁性，而不是
you in fact get M equals magnetization
equals zero or paramagnetism rather than
亚铁磁性顺磁性不是高温下的铁磁性
ferrimagnetism paramagnetism not
ferromagnetism at high temperature high
温度，这实际上比任何坚固的磁铁都更为典型
temperature and this is actually quite
typical than any firm magnet if you
在某个时候升高温度，顺磁性就会消失，您
raise it in temperature at some point
the pro magnetism will go away and you
有这样的直觉，这就是
have this sort of intuition that what's
that's coming from is that the the
瞬间的温度波动很大，以至于最终停止
moments are fluctuating thermally around
so much that they eventually stop
指向任何特定方向，如果不指向，则不指向任何方向
pointing in any particular direction and
they don't point in any if they're not
指向任何特定的方向，它不再是铁磁体，并且
pointing in any particular direction
it's not a ferromagnet anymore and in
事实上，这将在几分钟内成为一个顺磁性小表演，现在其他
fact it will be a paramagnet a little
show in a few moments okay now the other
可能是因为我们处于低温状态，所以请考虑一下
possibility is it we're at low
temperature so think about that
可能低温，在这种情况下双曲正切
possibility low temperature in which
case the hyperbolic tangent is a much
这样的曲线比较陡，因为双曲正切的参数是
steeper curve like this because the
argument of the hyperbolic tangent is
较大，因为在低温下β较大，因此实际上有三个
larger because beta is larger at low
temperature and so in fact there's three
解决方案，所以这是低温曲线，低温，所以我们有一个
solutions so this is the low temperature
curve low temperature so we have a
这里的解叫Sigma N等于T，在0处有一个解
solution here call that Sigma naught of
T there's a solution at 0 and then
这里有一个解决方案，我们称其为负Sigma naught
there's a solution here which we'll call
minus Sigma naught
茶，所以我们得到三到三个解决方案，三个解决方案分别是Sigma等于
tea so we get three to three solutions
three solutions which are Sigma equals
零，然后加上或减去T的Sigma零就将事实设为零
zero and then plus or minus Sigma naught
of T turn on zero the fact that we have
Sigma的非零解告诉我们我们有一个铁磁体，
nonzero solutions for Sigma it's telling
us that we have a ferromagnet and
铁磁体自然可以使其向上旋转或可以使其旋转
naturally the ferromagnet can have it
spins pointing up or it can have its
向下旋转，所以这些是铁磁解决方案，这不是
spins pointing down so these are the
ferromagnetic solutions and this is not
令人惊讶，因为我们知道如果您将温度降至零
surprising because we know that if you
go down to zero temperature this curve
事实上，它将变得非常陡峭
will be extremely steep it will
intersect right here as a matter of fact
然后您将完全意识到西格玛对西格玛的期望是
and you'll get complete polarization
that Sigma the expectation of Sigma is
1/2表示所有旋转都指向完全相同的方向，这样
1/2 meaning all the spins point in
exactly the same direction okay so that
将是您在零温度和更高温度下得到的
would be what you get at zero
temperature at higher temperature the
交点向下移动到稍低的点，您会变小
intersection moves down to a slightly
lower point and you get slightly smaller
Sigma的T值没有，所以磁化强度略小，但不为零
Sigma naught of T so you get slightly
smaller magnetization but not zero
磁化现在我们可能想知道这个家伙呢，我们还有另一个
magnetization now we might wonder what
about this guy here we have another
告诉我们我们期望Sigma为0的解决方案
solution which tells us we have an
expectation of Sigma being 0 and this
一个人实际上是有点困惑，事实证明这不是一个物理解决方案
one actually is a little puzzling it
turns out it's a not a physical solution
不是身体上的，您实际上会证明这是您的一项作业
not physical and you'll actually show
that for one of your homework
作业，所以事实证明您要做的作业是
assignments so it turns out what you'll
show for your homework is that this
我们求解的自洽方程实际上与x Extra相同
self-consistent equation that we solve
is actually the same thing as x extra
玉米释放出一种自由能，正如您所知，当您额外将一些玉米化时，您可以
maizing a free energy and as you know
when you extra Mize something you can
要么得到最大值，要么得到最小值，所以我们得到了-我们得到了一个最大值
either get a maximum or a minimum so
we're get-- we're getting one maximum
而自由能的两个最小值，最小值是自由能
and two minima of the free energies the
minimum are the free energies are the
物理上实现的东西和最大的自由能是排序的
things that are realized physically and
the maximum of the free energy is sort
会从方程式中得出错误，但这在物理上还不行，
of a mistake it comes out of the
equations but it's not physical okay and
当您实际写下自由能时，它会更加清晰
it's much clearer when you actually
write down the free energy which you'll
做功课，您会明白为什么我们不保留该解决方案，所以这
do for homework and you'll see why it is
that we don't keep that solution so this
我们有点忽略，我们只跟踪这些铁磁解决方案
one we sort of ignore and we only keep
track of these ferromagnetic solutions
好吧，我们想知道在什么温度下
okay
so we'd like to know at what temperature
从做强磁铁变成做费罗磁铁，我们这样写
do we go from being a power magnet to
being a Ferro magnet let's write that
在什么茶下喝什么铁
down at what T
at what tea do we get ferromagnetism
嗯，实际上有一个TC的名称比您得到的TC小/ T
well there's actually a name for that TC
is known as a / T less than TC you get
铁磁性farrell mag和TC被称为居里温度Curie tam
ferromagnetism farrell mag and TC is
known as the curie temperature curie tam
或临界温度临界温度，低于此温度则为Ferro
or the critical temperature critical
temp below which you have Ferro
磁性，所以我们想知道什么时候获得TC或何时获得
magnetism so we'd like to know when do
we get what is TC or when do we get this
铁磁磁性在什么温度以下都可以看到
Ferro magnetism below what temperature
well the way to see that again looking
图形化地认识到拥有一个解决方案之间的过渡
graphically is to realize that the
transition between having one solution
当双曲正切函数为
having three solutions occurs when the
hyperbolic tangent the function is
与y完全相切的Sigma线与
exactly tangent to the y equals Sigma
line where it lines up just exactly with
相同的斜率，这就是重点所在的原因
the same slope and the reason that
that's the important point where where
从顺磁性到铁磁性的转变是
the where you have the transition from
paramagnetism to Ferro magnetism is
因为如果双曲正切不那么陡峭，您将只有一个
because if the hyperbolic tangent were
any less steep you'd have only one
解决方案，如果还有更多解决方案，您可以采用三种解决方案，因此我们必须
solution and if it were any more steep
you have three solutions so we have to
寻找双曲正切具有完全相同的情况
look for the for the situation where the
hyperbolic tangent has exactly the same
斜率y等于Sigma，所以TC从找到切线X的切线斜率开始
slope is y equals Sigma okay so TC from
finding slope of tangent of tangent X
在此处平移y等于切线tantra设置等于1的斜率是beta jay-z
pand the y equals tangent here the slope
of tantra set equal to one is beta jay-z
超过四个或只是重新排列一点，我们得到KB TC等于四个以上的JZ
over four or just rearranging a little
bit we get KB T C equals JZ over four
这是温度的关键值，还可以吗？
which is the critical value of
temperature okay is everyone still with
我还算开心，不，是的，嗯，也许好吧，让我暂停一下
me fairly fairly happy no yes maybe okay
um maybe alright so let me just pause
好一秒钟，现在是时候喝巧克力了
for a second to sort of okay well it's
time for chocolate actually so um so for
对于一块巧克力棒，杰伊-z认为什么至关重要？
for one chocolate bar what's the what's
the critical importance of jay-z think
开箱即用，真的很好，谁说我
outside the box
well it's really good who said that I
会说他已经嫁给了碧昂丝，但已经足够亲密了
was gonna say he's married to Beyonce
but it's close enough
是的，所以很好，是的，没有，杰伊-z除了我之外，碧昂丝阿姨
yeah so yeah very good yeah okay no did
jay-z is besides me auntie Beyonce the
Jay-z的重要性在这里，实际上是在告诉您，
importance of jay-z here is that it's in
fact it's telling you that okay one
母亲花花公子知道碧昂斯的中间名，你知道那是她的最后一次
mother dudes anyone know beyoncé's
middle name do you know that's her last
名字不，不，那是你姐姐的名字，是的，不，不，甚至都不知道，
name no no that's your sister's name
yeah come on no no didn't even know and
碧昂斯（Beyonce）的宝宝的名字，是的，有人在那边买了，是的，我有一个
Beyonce's baby's name yeah someone got
it over there yes yeah okay I have one
对你来说还好吧，所以好吧，jay-z的重要之处是
for you also alright okay so does okay
um the important of jay-z here is
实际上，这是自旋与其邻居耦合的总能量
actually it's a total amount of energy
of coupling of the spin to its neighbors
所以我们这里有Z个邻居，J是
and so we have Z neighbors here and J is
the amount of the coupling strength from
旋转到它的每个邻居，所以当温度高于
the spin to each of its neighbors so
when the temperature gets above the
与其邻居的耦合强度总量，热波动
total amount of coupling strength to its
neighbors the fluctuation in the thermal
这种旋转的波动使它想要停留在
fluctuations of that spin so overwhelm
the amount that it wants to stay in the
与邻居的方向相同，这就是它想要的铁磁体的原因
same direction as its neighbors which is
what's keeping it a ferromagnet it wants
与邻居有相同的方向，当能量
to have the same direction as its
neighbors and when the energy of the
热能刚好大于将其保持在原位的能量
thermal energy is just greater than the
energy holding it in place
你会失去铁磁性，好吧，这就是这张照片背后的直觉
you lose ferromagnetism okay that's the
intuition behind this picture here
好吧，好吧，至少可以在图形上拍摄这张照片，
alright alright anyway so at least
graphically we can take this picture and
我们可以将Sigma作为T的函数进行求解，只需找出
we can solve for Sigma as a function of
T you just have to figure out where
当我们改变T时，有两条曲线交叉，我们将得到一张图片，
where there's two curves cross as we
change T and we'll get a picture that
看起来有点像这里的温度
looks kind of like this here's
temperature
这是零温度下的Sigma Sigma实际上是一半，因为所有
here's Sigma at zero temperature Sigma
is actually a half because all all the
自旋对齐，然后在TCC处变为零，
spins are aligned
and then at TCC it goes to zero and
高于TC，则完全为零，但随后下降到这样的水平
above above TC it's exactly zero but
then it comes down kind of like this at
改变T的温度是有限的，所以实际上
finite temperature as you've changed T
so this is actually gives you the
所得到的魔力是多少的状态方程是一个函数
equation of state of how much Magn is a
ssin you get is a function of
温度，您可以从这个平均场近似中得到它，这并不精确
temperature and you can get it from this
mean field approximation it's not exact
但这是相当不错的，所以最后一步是我向你保证
but it's it's fairly good okay all right
so the last step is that I promised you
在这个地区，我们有一个顺磁性，所以我们应该拒绝
that up in this region here we have a
paramagnet so we should reject and
说服自己这确实是一个顺磁性，而做到这一点的一种方法是
convince ourselves it really is a
paramagnet and one way to do that is to
计算磁化率，以便我们知道的事情就在该区域
calculate susceptibility so things that
we know is up in this region if you
如果不施加磁场，则不施加磁场sigma为0
don't apply a magnetic field sigma is 0
if you apply a small magnetic field then
sigma可能接近0，所以我们可以做的就是
sigma is probably gonna be close to 0 so
what we can do is we can take our
原始的自洽方程，我们可以将其扩展为
original self-consistency equation and
we can expand it for small argument of
双曲正切，因为里面的所有东西都是根据定义
the hyperbolic tangent because
everything inside there is by definition
小C西格玛小B小小一切都小，所以我们可以写
small C the Sigma is smaller B is small
everything is small so we can write
西格玛等于，她只是把这全部写下来，我要吸收一些
Sigma equals and she's just writing this
all out I'm going to absorb a couple of
此处的负号beta超过2的JC Sigma负值超过2磁场的beta G mu B
minus signs here beta J C Sigma over 2
minus beta G mu B over 2 magnetic field
好的，然后我们重新安排它，以便我们将Sigma作为
ok and then we just rearrange this in so
we solve for Sigma as a function of
磁场，这样我们就可以得到Sigma IPL，即1减去JZ超过4个beta等于
magnetic field we get Sigma IPL right
this way 1 minus JZ over 4 beta equals
减去βGμB超过4倍的磁场，这一点是
minus beta G mu B over 4 times the
magnetic field and this notice this
这里的数量实际上是TC，是KBT，因此我们进行了一些重新排列
quantity here is actually TC is KBT see
so with a little bit more rearranging we
得到的西格玛等于负1/4 GμB磁场B除以KBT减去KB
get Sigma equals minus 1/4 G mu B
magnetic field B divided by KBT minus KB
TC，然后我们实际上希望将其转换为某种敏感性
TC and then we want to actually convert
this into some sort of susceptibility so
磁矩为负G mu B Sigma和磁化强度，所以这是
the magnetic moment is minus G mu B
Sigma and magnetization so this is a
可见时刻，磁化强度是每个站点的时间乘以Rho
moment for sight the magnetization is
the moment per site times Rho the
旋转密度旋转密度然后是
density of spins density of spins and
then the susceptibility will be mu
根据定义，dm DB在b处等于零，这只是插入了一对
naught by definition d m DB at b equals
zero which just plugging in a couple
在这里排队，然后得到KBT的1/4 rhg g b平方平方
lines up here we get then get 1/4 rho g
mu b squared mu naught over KBT
1乘以1减去TC乘以t，这整个数量实际上是
times 1 over 1 minus TC over t and this
whole quantity here is actually the
居里磁化率居里自旋1/2，换句话说就是我们的磁化率
Curie susceptibility curie for a spin
1/2 in other words its susceptibility we
本来可以计算出我们只是自由旋转1/2，实际上这正是我们
would have calculated we've just a free
spin 1/2 in fact it is exactly what we
当我们计算自旋1/2 in的磁化率时计算
calculated when we calculated the
magnetic susceptibility of a spin 1/2 in
最后一堂课，然后整个结果乘以1减去1
the last lecture but then this whole
thing gets multiplied by 1 over 1 minus
TC超过t，所以我们的权力巨头对TC的敏感性是
TC over t so the susceptibility of our
power magnate above TC is a
只是一个与每个都不耦合的自由旋转1/2系统的磁化率
susceptibility of just a system of free
spin 1/2 which aren't coupled to each
其他和至少在免疫中耦合在缓和模型中的作用
other and the effect of the coupling in
the easing model at least with immune
场论就是将它乘以T的1减去TC
field theory is to multiply it by this
factor of 1 minus TC over T ok now you
可能会注意到在临界温度或居里温度下
may notice that at the critical
temperature or the Curie temperature
这个因素有所不同，实际上是物理上的，这是真实的，其原因
this factor diverges and that actually
is physical it's real and the reason
是因为存在，因为我们必须记住，这种敏感性
it's it's there is because we have to
remember that that the susceptibility
告诉你打开一点点的磁化强度
tells you how much magnetization you get
when you turn on a little bit of
磁场的定义，但当您低于临界点时
magnetic field by its definition but
when you go below the critical
温度即使在0磁场下也会磁化，因此
temperature you get magnetization even
for 0 magnetic fields so the
易感性一定已经使无穷大了
susceptibility must have gotten the
infinite somewhere along a little on the
行，这就是这个词在这里所做的，好吧，所以这是
line so that's what this term is doing
there ok all right so this is the
平均场理论的一般方案及其工作原理
general scheme of a mean field theory
and how it works
平均场论在哪里，是的平均场论
mean field theory where was it yeah mean
field theory
通常如何以平均方式近似某个算子
how it works where we generally
approximate some operator by an average
并且这种平均场理论技术可以更广泛地使用
and this technique of mean field theory
can be used much much more generally
比我们在这里做作业所要讲的平均场论
than what we did here for homework
you'll do a mean field theory
反铁磁体的计算以及轮渡磁体的计算
calculation for an antiferromagnet as
well you could do it for a ferry magnet
您可以将其旋转不到一半的事实
you could do it for spins that aren't
spin one-half the fact that we got a
整个故事中的双曲线正切来自于这样一个事实：
hyperbolic tangent in this in this whole
story came from the fact that we were
考虑它旋转一半，所以如果我们旋转，它只会旋转向上和向下旋转
thinking about it spin one-half so it
had only spin up and spin down if we
在考虑自旋一时，我们将使自旋s D等于1 SZ等于0在Z
were thinking about spin one we would
have spin s D equals 1 SZ equals 0 at Z
等于负1，我们会得到比双曲正切更复杂的东西
equals minus 1 we'd get something more
complicated than a hyperbolic tangent
我们会得到一个所谓的Brewin函数，但是关于您如何使用的一般主题
we'd get a so called Brewin function but
the general themes of how you how you
使其准确地对待系统的一部分，然后坚持
approach it treat one piece of the
system exactly and then insist on
自我一致性保持不变，并且该技术在外部使用
self-consistency that remains the same
and the technique is used outside of
凝聚态的磁性用于理解液晶
magnetism in condensed matter it's used
for understanding liquid crystals it's
用于了解流感动力学，用于天体物理学，用于
used for understanding flu dynamics is
used in astrophysics it's used in
大气物理学平均场理论只是一种非常普遍的技术
atmospheric physics mean field theory is
just a very general technique that's
用于许多事情，对您有好处，可以将其思想内部化
used for many many things and it's good
to you know internalize the ideas of it
好吧，我们将使用均值场理论来做另一件事
alright we were going to use mean field
theory for one more thing which is to
了解流动铁磁性流动剂是下一个主题
understand itinerant ferromagnetism
itinerant which is the next subject an
流动磁力和“流动”一词的意思是基本上漂泊
itinerant magnetism and the word the
word itinerant means wandering basically
或有时它意味着迷失，但眼睛真正的意思是
or sometimes it means lost but the eye
what it really means is that the
磁矩由移动电子携带
magnetic moment moments are carried are
carried by mobile electrons by mobile
自从几年前我们开始谈论磁性以来，我们现在的电子
electrons now since we started talking
about magnetism a couple lectures ago we
考虑将磁矩放在站点上，磁矩可以
thought about putting magnetic moments
on sites and the magnetic moments could
向不同的方向移动，但我们没有考虑这种可能性
move in point in different directions
but we didn't consider the possibility
瞬间实际上可以从一个站点跳到另一个站点，但实际上
that the moments could actually hop from
one site to another site but in real
像铁这样的磁铁是非常典型的，
magnets like an iron for example is
quite typical that the same things that
这些电子实际上也在四处移动
are giving you a magnetization these
electrons are actually moving around too
乐队，但他们设法给我们铁磁性，就像其他类型的
in bands and yet they managed to give us
ferromagnetism so as with other types of
磁力流动磁力是由相互作用产生的
magnetism itinerant magnetism is driven
by interactions it comes from the
电子之间的相互作用来自相互作用，所以我们必须以某种方式
interaction between electrons from from
interactions so somehow we have to
引入互动并至少在一定的平均范围内对待他们
introduce interactions and treat them at
least within some mean field
为了了解迭代磁，现在当然要进行一次近似
approximation in order to understand
itinerant magnetism now of course once
您开始介绍电子之间的相互作用事情变得复杂
you start introducing interactions
between electrons things get complicated
很快，所以我们需要一个非常简化的模型
very quickly so we need a very
simplified model which will represent
电子之间的相互作用，仍然赋予我们正确的权利
the interaction between electrons and
still give us the right the right
物理学，所以我们要使用的模型就是所谓的Hubbard模型Hubbard
physics so the model we're going to use
is the so-called Hubbard model Hubbard
于1963年写下此书以试图了解流动磁场
wrote this down in 1963 to try to
understand itinerant magnetism and since
他写下来的话哈伯德模型拥有自己的巨大生命
he wrote this down the Hubbard model has
taken on a huge life of its own
它可能是相互作用电子的最重要模型
it's potentially it is probably the most
important model of interacting electrons
在所有物理学中都可能毫不夸张地说
in all of physics there have been
probably without exaggeration a hundred
关于Hubbard模型主题的数千篇论文是如此重要
thousand papers written on the subject
of the Hubbard model it's that important
之所以如此重要，是因为它异常出色
to the field and the reason it's so
important is because it's exceptionally
很简单，但是它的物理却非常复杂，所以哈伯德的方式
simple and yet its physics is quite
complex so but the way Hubbard
您知道在均值领域理论中对它的处理方法
you know treated it in mean field
theories what we're going to do here
这很简单，您可以获得很好的结果，这有助于您理解
it's fairly simple you get out a good
result which helps you understand
流动铁磁性，这就是我们要在模型中要做的
itinerant ferromagnetism which is what
we're going to do in the model it's
很简单，我们要做的是写一个哈密顿量
pretty straightforward what we do is we
start by writing a Hamiltonian that is
紧密结合紧密结合电子与一些跳跃
tight binding tight binding tight
binding electrons with hopping with some
跳变T和紧密结合电子的哈密顿量的这一部分
hopping T and this part of the
Hamiltonian of tight binding electrons
经过一些跳跃，我们已经解决了这个问题，然后才在
with some hopping we've solved this
before we looked at this earlier in the
术语，我们得到了这些余弦形带，您可以填充余弦形带
term we got these cosine shaped bands
you can fill up the cosine shaped bands
如果是半满的乐队，你会得到一个金属，如果是一个完整的乐队，你会得到一个
if it's a half filled band you get a
metal if it's a full band you get an
绝缘体，但绝不仅仅具有这种类型的结合电子
insulator but never in just this model
here with just type binding electrons
跳就可以得到铁磁体
with hopping would you ever get
ferromagnets
如果只有这种紧密的绑定结构，您将永远不会遇到任何情况
ism you'd never get a situation if you
only have this tight binding structure
你从哪里下来会有不同数量的上升时刻
you where you would ever have a
different number of up moments from down
时刻他们总是会出来的，所以我们必须添加一些东西
moments they would always come out even
so we have to add something to it which
将会改变故事以及我们要添加的内容
is going to change the story and what
we're adding to it
是我指定您使用的某些总体网站的互动条件大于
is the interaction term some overall
sites I parameter you use greater than
零倍于站点上的电子数量，我们自旋向上乘以
zero times the number of electrons on
site I we spin up times the number of
我们旋转的站点上的电子，然后写下这是电子的数量
electrons on site I we spin down then
write this this is number of electrons
在现场，我向下旋转就可以了，所以这是在告诉我
on site I with spin up down down okay so
what this is doing is this just telling
你，每当两个电子坐在你身上，你就会受到能量的惩罚
you that you get an energy penalty of
you whenever two electrons sit on the
同一站点上的相同原子好吧，我们实际上已经讨论过了
same atom on the same site okay and
we've actually discussed this
哈密​​顿量，我们没有使用“哈伯德模型”一词，但提醒您何时
Hamiltonian before we didn't use the
word Hubbard model but remind you when
我们讨论了Mod绝缘子Mod绝缘子我们讨论了一种情况
we talked about mod insulators mod
insulators we discussed a situation
电子之间的相互作用是如此强烈，以至于你只能将一个
where the interaction between electrons
was so strong that you can only put a
该站点上的单个电子，然后您会得到一个情况
single electron on the site and then you
get you can get a situation if there's a
现场只有一个电子，然后一切都冻结在交通堵塞中，因为没有
single electron on site then everything
gets frozen in a traffic jam because no
可以跳到附近的站点，因为已经有人坐在
one can hop to the neighboring site
because there's already someone sitting
在那里，即使您有一个看起来像应该是
there and even though you have a
something that looks like it should be a
半填充禁令您仍然拥有称为Mott绝缘子的绝缘子
half-filled ban you still have an
insulator known as a Mott insulator so
这与我们将要允许自己打开的物理学完全相同
this is exactly the same physics we're
just going to allow ourselves to turn on
然后通过这种互动，您可以使它像我们想要的那样强大或像我们想要的那样脆弱
and off that interaction you make it as
strong as we want or as weak as we want
好吧，所以不太复杂看起来像一个非常简单的模型，但这又是其中之一
okay so not too complicated looks like a
very simple model but again it's one of
这些模型看起来很简单，但不是一维可解决的，
these models it looks simple but it
isn't it's solvable in one dimension and
尽管有十万篇论文，对此一无所知
absolutely nothing is known about it
despite a hundred thousand papers
以更高的尺寸写在上面，好吧，也许不是绝对，但是，但是
written on it in higher dimensions okay
maybe not absolutely nothing but but but
没有我们想要的那么多，这就是为什么人们不断写论文的原因
not as much as we would like which is
why people keep writing papers about it
好吧，那么我们该如何对待这个第一件事呢？
okay so how do we treat this well first
thing we're going to do we're going to
按照以下形式编写此交互项，将其写为u over
write this interaction term as in the
following form will write it as u over
四个，上下加减四个
four and up plus and down minus u over
four
和向上平方负n向上负n负平方，所以这只是一个标识
and up up squared minus n up minus n
down squared so that's just an identity
这很容易，我们没有做任何不同的事情
that's easy we haven't done anything
different here what we're going to do
现在是我们要使均值场近似均值场
now is we're going to make the mean
field approximation mean field which
表示字段总是以某种方式或其他方式表示您所处位置的平均值
mean field always somehow or other means
take something's average where you're
不允许通过取平均值和什么来做不正确的事情
not allowed to do something that's
incorrect by taking an average and what
我们要做的是，这是不正确的，因为我们要采取
we're going to do which is not quite
correct is we're going to take an
这些项的平均值，因此我们将取n的平均值加上n的最小值和
average of these terms so we're going to
take average of n up plus n down and
将其减去您的平方，平均得到n减去n的平均值，然后平方就可以了
square it minus you over for average of
n up minus n down and square it okay so
这是平均场近似值，或者是平均场的一种类型
that's the mean field approximation or
it's one type of mean field
我们将要使用的近似值，我们需要先查看它给我们带来的好处
approximation we're going to use and we
need to see what it gives us well first
在这所有学期中，平均n个提出请求的发送总数
of all this term here average of n up
put send down that's just a total
密度电子的总密度总密度是固定的
density total number of electrons total
density and that's fixed probably fixed
在一天的开始，根据您所拥有的条件，
at the beginning of the day by the
conditions that you have so that's just
要给第一个名词要给我们一个常数
going to give that first term is going
to give us a constant the interesting
这是这个名词的意思-结束实际上是每个站点的时刻
thing is this term here that ennop - end
down is actually the moment per site
除以玻尔磁子，然后取平方，所以减去u
divided by the Bohr Magneton and then
it's gets squared so minus u over for a
瞬间除以Bohr Magneton平方，因为
moment divided by the Bohr Magneton
square right because the number of
分拆产生的旋转可能是网站上的磁矩，所以我们
spin-offs might have spin downs is the
magnetic moment on the site okay so we
可以重写这个交互项是一些我们不感兴趣的常数
can rewrite this interaction term is
some constant which we're not interested
减去你的四分之一，然后我将这一刻重写为磁化强度
in minus u over four and then I'm going
to rewrite this moment as magnetization
乘以单位B的面积乘以mu B平方，因此V等于单位体积
times the volume of the unit cell over
mu B squared so V equals volume of unit
单元格，之所以这样重写，是因为我想拥有
cell and the reason I'm rewriting it
that way is because I'd like to have
这东西作为磁化和磁化具有矩量
this thing as a magnetization and
magnetization has dimensions of moment
每单位体积，所以我必须放入单位体积的体积
per unit volume so I have to put in a
the volume of unit cell to have the
尺寸出来正确没关系，需要注意的是
dimensions come out right okay and the
thing to notice about this is that the
能量随着磁化强度变大，相互作用能变小
energy the interaction energy gets
smaller as the magnetization gets larger
为什么那么直觉实际上
why is that
well the intuition for that actually
如果所有自旋都在其他位置对齐，则来自保利排除原则
comes from the Pauli exclusion principle
if all the spins were aligned in other
如果磁化强度最大，那么就不会有相互作用
words if the magnetization were maximum
then there would be no interaction
能量，因为你永远不会有两个电子坐着的情况
energy whatsoever because you can never
have a situation where two electrons sat
在同一站点上，您仅需在有
on the same site and you only have to
pay this energy penalty when there are
同一位置上的两个电子，因此，如果您在同一位置极化所有自旋
two electrons on the same site so if you
polarize all your spins in the same
方向，您将获得尽可能小的交互能量，这就是为什么
direction you get the minimum possible
interaction energy and that's why it is
如果增加磁化强度，则下降的相互作用能是
if you increase the magnetization you
drop the interaction energy is that
清除好，好吧，从这张照片来看
clear
good all right so from this picture it
让您认为然后就可以了，一旦您打开了所有自旋的互动
makes you think then okay once you turn
on the interaction all the spins want to
对齐，但这并不容易，因为对齐旋转会降低您的动力
align but it's not so easy because
aligning the spins cost you kinetic
能量，你必须要让这两件事与之抗争
energy and you have to you have to sort
of let these two things fight it out
彼此，所以让我们提醒自己动力学发生了什么
with each other so let's remind
ourselves what happens to the kinetic
能量随着您改变系统的磁体而变化我们现在已经研究过了
energy as you change the magnet of a
system now we studied this before so if
您还记得我们在第一周保利·帕拉磁铁所做的保罗顺磁性
you recall pauli paramagnetism which we
did in the first week Pauli para magnet
旋转状态与能量状态的关系，看起来像这样，然后我们有
of states of spin up versus energy it
kind of looks like this and then we have
我们向下旋转的状态密度与能量的关系，
the density of states we spin down
versus energy and it looks exactly the
一样，如果没有磁化，则将它们填充到同一水平
same and if there's no magnetization you
fill them both up to the same level this
听起来对Polly磁力很熟悉
sounds familiar from Polly power
magnetism
现在，如果您想使它们看起来应该相同，如果您想
now if you want to make those are
supposed to look identical if you want
拥有非零磁化强度，您需要做的是
to have a nonzero magnetization what you
have to do is you have to take some of
旋转并使其旋转，为此，我们将其中的一小部分
the spin downs and make them spin ups so
to do that let's take a sliver of these
旋转下来，我们必须将它们向上移动到更高的能量，所以这会花费您
spin downs and we have to move them up
to higher energy up here so it costs you
能量，所以这些应该对齐，所以要花费您精力
energy so these were supposed to be
aligned that so it costs you energy to
磁化强度不为零，动能消耗为非零
have a non zero magnetization it cost
you kinetic energy to have a non zero
磁化还可以，所以我们节省了一些相互作用能，但是却消耗了动力学
magnetization alright so we saved some
interaction energy but it cost kinetic
能量，所以我们必须权衡这些，以便计算
energy so we have to trade those off
against each other so in order to figure
要弄清楚这些是如何相互对抗的，我们必须弄清楚它们之间有多少
out how those are battle against each
other we have to figure out how much
能量实际上会花费您一些非零磁化强度，所以让我们
energy it actually costs you to have
some nonzero magnetization so let's do
所以首先我们要回到保利
that
so first we'll go back to the Pauli
功率磁计算，我们将为您设置
power magnetic calculation so we're
going to set you
零秒，所以现在我们回到非相互作用的电子，我是
to zero for a second so now we're back
to non-interacting electrons and I'm
将要写出的自由能是磁化强度的函数
going to write the free energy as a
function of magnetization as a function
单位体积的磁化强度，那么负m点BI会认为
magnetization per unit volume and that
will then the minus m dot B I think
每个人都可能会接受应该有一个这样的术语
everyone's probably will accept that
that's there should be a term like that
想要使磁化强度与自由能减m点B一致
in the free energy minus m dot B that
wants the magnetization to align with
与外部磁场，但第二项不那么明显，但
the with the external magnetic field but
then the second term is less obvious but
它采用M Squared mu形式，比Pauli磁化率高2倍
it takes the form M Squared mu naught
over 2 times the Pauli susceptibility
保利强力磁化率，我只想提醒您我们已经计算了
Pauli power magnetic susceptibility and
I'll just remind you we calculated this
在科德·保利（Paul Paul）嗨的学期的第一周，波莉（Polly）是喵
in the in the first week of the term
that cod Pauli was hi Polly is Mew
零μB平方乘以费米能量处的态密度就可以做到
naught mu B squared times the density of
states at the Fermi energy does that
听起来有点熟悉，现在我为什么写下来
kind of sound familiar
ok now why is it that I wrote down this
这里的术语比较复杂，为什么我认为这首先是正确的
complicated terms here why do I think
this is correct well first of all this
是磁化过程中的泰勒膨胀，所以在
is sort of a Taylor expansion in the
magnetization so this is linear in
磁化原理上存在二次方
magnetization there's a quadratic in
magnetization in principle there would
以及更高的术语，我们将忽略，因为我们有兴趣
be higher terms as well which we're
going to ignore because we're interested
通常以小磁化强度x'表示，但是为什么我不给这个名词
in small magnetization x' in general but
why would I give it this term mu naught
超过2个奇保利井，事实证明，它实际上必须具有这种形式，并且
over 2 Chi Pauli well it turns out that
it actually has to have this form and to
看到它必须具有这种形式，我们知道自由能应该是
see that it has to have this form we
know that the free energy should be
应该最小化，以便FDM必须等于零，并且
should be minimized
so the FDM has to equal zero and that
告诉我在R Chi Polly上减去的负B加M mu必须等于零，并且
tells me that minus B plus M mu naught
over R Chi Polly has to equal zero and
如果您只是重新排列，那就告诉我磁化作用是奇保利
if you just rearrange that that tells me
that the magnetization is Chi Pauli over
零倍磁场定义了奇保利
mu naught times the magnetic field which
is what defines Chi Pauli
保利对我们的自由电子气的敏感性的定义
the definition of the Pauli
susceptibility for our free electron gas
磁化强度应该是Kuip oli乘以磁场，从而表明
is the magnetization should be Kuip oli
times the magnetic field so that tells
我的自由能量必须具有我刚刚写下的形式
me the free energy has to have that form
that I just wrote down ok
这可能是您可能会经历的痛苦中的一招
it's a little bit of a trick you could
go through the agony of trying to
实际计算磁化强度能量是磁化强度的函数
actually calculate the magnetization the
energy is a function of magnetization
您会得到相同的结果，您会发现它必须以这种方式出现
you get the same result you would
discover it has to come out this way
好的，所以让我们关闭set set，将外部字段set B设为零
okay so so then let's turn off set set
the external field set B equal to zero
然后打开你不等于零的能量，那么我们得到的自由能是
and turn turn you on you not equal to
zero and then the free energy we get is
将是我们刚刚计算出的两个条件的组合
going to be a combination of the two
terms that we just calculated so free
那么每单位体积的能量就可以了，我们在这里将其关闭B，所以我
energy per volume is then well okay we
have this term here it turned off B so I
只是让M平方数变成了CAI poly的零，然后也要滚动
just get M squared nu naught over to CAI
poly but then also just about to scroll
顶上的减号是您的四倍
off the top
there's minus u over four times well
好的d覆盖在mu b平方的DZ平方的子像素上，我将得到
okay d squared over mu b squared DZ
squared of subdennis I'm going to get
除去V磁化强度的平方好，什么是V平方，但现在它将
rid of a V magnetization squared okay
what is V squared but now it's going to
是V，因为我写的是每单位体积的自由能，而不是
be V because I'm writing the free energy
per unit volume not the free energy in
这种情况好吧，所以我掉了一个体积的因子，所以这些正方形不他妈的
this case okay so I dropped a factor of
a volume so it's not these squares
是V好吧，我想这是可以排除M的原因，所以我们有M
is V alright so what this is I guess we
can factor out the M so we have M
平方，然后超过2个chi poly-您通过mu B平方超过4 V
squared and then u naught over 2 chi
poly - you over 4 V over mu B squared
这告诉我们，会有更高的术语两个术语是
and this tells us and there will be
higher terms two terms which are
四分之一的磁化强度，等等
quartered akin in magnetization and so
forth which are not interested in but
这里要意识到的关键是括号中的这个值是否小于0
the key thing to realize here is if this
thing in the brackets is less than 0
那么磁化强度就想不为零
then the magnetization wants to be
nonzero
如果方括号中的东西大于0，那么磁化强度在哪里
where is if the thing in the brackets is
greater than 0 then the magnetization
想要设为0还好，那么这个准则就是法罗铁磁性的准则
wants to be 0 okay so the criterion so
criterion for ferromagnetism for farro
被称为斯托纳准则斯托纳准则是
which is known as the stoner criterion
stoner criterion is that this mu naught
超过2个Chi Poli-您的单位晶胞体积超过
over 2 Chi Poli - you volume of the unit
cell over
或玻尔磁子平方应小于零，因此当您打开
or bohr magneton squared should be less
than zero so when you turn on the
相互作用强度足够强，则相互作用强度就可以胜出
interaction strength strong enough then
the interaction strength wins and it
想要使自旋极化两极分化，而如果相互作用不强
wants to have this the spins polarize
whereas if the interaction is not strong
足够多，那么实际上具有相同数量的旋转和
enough then in fact it's more beneficial
to have an equal number of spin ups and
降低转速，因为您实际上可以这样节省动能
spin downs because you save kinetic
energy that way way actually we can
只需在Kai Poly的定义中将其重写即可
rewrite this in a just putting in the
definition of Kai poly we can write this
因为单位单元的体积乘以u乘以G的TF应该大于2
as volume of the unit cell times u times
G a TF should be greater than two
等价的好，所以这就是我们从
equivalent okay so that's what we get
out of this mean field approximation for
弄清楚什么时候我们有铁磁性，但是有趣的事情之一
figuring out when we have ferromagnetism
but one of the things that's interesting
关于哈伯模型，您还可以获得哈伯反铁磁性哈伯
about the hubbard model is you can also
get a hubbard antiferromagnetism hubbard
反铁磁性反铁磁性，当我们使用大的U
anti ferromagnetism anti ferromagnetism
and this occurs when we have use large u
每个位点有一个大的电子，因此处于Mott绝缘体状态Mott
large and one electron per site so this
is in the Mott insulator regime Mott
绝缘体，因此，如果u大，则可以防止每个位置有两个电子
insulator so if u is large it prevents
you from having two electrons per site
或基本上可以防止这种情况，然后由于每个位点只有一个电子，因此
or mostly prevents that and then since
it's one electron per site you have this
电子的交通阻塞，您在每个位置上只有一个电子
traffic jam of electrons where you have
exactly one electron on every site and
说服自己这件事将成为我们阿姨的方式
the way to convince yourself that this
thing is going to be an auntie for our
磁铁是要尝试两种可能性，因此一种情况是考虑使用铁磁体
magnet is to try the two possibilities
so case one it is consider a ferromagnet
情况一被认为是铁磁体达拉磁体，所以我们有很多自旋
case one is considered a ferromagnet
daraa magnet so we have a bunch of spins
每个电子都带有自旋，它们位于每个位置，它们都对齐，并且
electrons each with their spin sitting
on each site they're all aligned and the
这种情况下的能量实际上为零基态的能量为
energy of this situation is actually
zero the energy of the ground state is
正好为零，而零为零的原因则是您永远无需支付任何互动
is exactly zero and the reason it's zero
is well you never pay any interaction
能量，因为根据泡利原理，没有电子坐在同一位置
energy because due to the Pauli
principle no electrons sit on the same
网站，所以您永远不必支付多晶硅价格，也不必支付u能源
site ever so you don't ever pay the poly
price you don't ever pay the u energy
而且电子根本不能从一个位置跳到另一个位置，因为
and also the electrons can't hop from
one site to the other at all because
交通堵塞，所以他们不能跳，所以
there's in the
traffic jam so they can't hop so the
跳跃的总能量现在也为零第二种可能性是
total energy of hopping is also zero
now the second possibility is that you
有一个反铁磁体的盒子可以放我们的磁体，这还多了一点
have an antiferromagnet case to ante for
our magnet and this is a little more
之所以复杂，是因为我们已经降低了速度，降低了速度，等等
complicated because we have spin up spin
down spin up spin down and so forth and
在这里，电子可以跳到
here
well an electron can hop to the
相邻站点，但必须为此付出一定的代价，这样您就可以旋转
neighboring site but it has to it has to
pay a price to do so so you'll get spin
向上旋转，您在这一侧将有0，然后在此侧，您将具有上下
up spin down you'll have 0 on this side
and then you have up-down on this side
它消耗了你的能量U，然后又在这边上升，所以这是一个兴奋的状态
which cost you energy U and then up on
this side so this is an excited state
这是一个有效的兴奋状态，可能会消耗一些能量，因此您可能会很大
which is a valid excited state it costs
you some energy you you might be large
但至少实际上你可以做这样的事情，所以二阶
but at least virtually you can make such
a thing and so in second-order
扰动理论由于这种跳跃过程，您在
perturbation Theory due to this sort of
hopping process you get a shift in the
所有可能的激发x'激发跳变之和的能量
energy which is sum over all possible
excitation x' excitation hopping
哈密​​尔顿基态平方于能量0减去能量激发态
hamiltonian ground state squared over
energy 0 minus energy excited state and
这小于0，所以实际上能量变化小于0，所以
this is less than 0 so in fact the
change in energy is less than 0 so
反铁磁的反铁磁能量小于一个
antiferromagnetic energy for
antiferromagnet is less than energy of a
当您在此莫特绝缘子中每个位点有一个电子时，铁磁体
ferromagnet when you have one electron
per site in this in this Mott insulator
现在限制，这似乎有点复杂，但让我改写一下
limit now this might seem a little
complicated but let me rephrase what we
如果您有铁磁体，那么就做，所以在铁磁体的情况下，每个电子
just did if you have a ferromagnet so in
the case of a ferromagnet each electron
基本上坐在一个无限高的井里，你不能跳到左边
is basically sitting in an infinitely
tall well you can't hop to the left it
不能跳到Pauli排除绝对禁止的右边
can't hop to the right that's absolutely
forbidden by the Pauli exclusion
原理，所以您应该将其视为无限地存在的电子
principle so you should think of it as
an electron sitting in the infinitely
高的井，而对于反铁磁体，您在有限的井中有一个电子
tall well whereas for an antiferromagnet
you have an electron in a finite well so
井的高度只有您自己，它可以跳至所需的邻近站点
the height of the well is only you it
can hop to the neighboring site it costs
能量u但它可以做到，但Pauli和
an energy u but it can do it it's not
forbidden by Pauli and the energy of the
具有有限势垒的反铁磁体比铁磁体的能量低
antiferromagnet with a finite barrier is
lower than the energy of the ferromagnet
具有无限的障碍，因此反铁磁体受到青睐，所以这是
with the infinite barrier so the
antiferromagnet is favored so this is
某种原因使反铁磁性有点，所以它使
sort of one of the things that makes the
anti ferromagnetism a little so it makes
哈伯德模型很有趣，它可以给你
the hubbard model
quite interesting that it can give you
反铁磁性它可以给您铁磁性它可以给您很多
anti ferromagnetism it can give you
ferrimagnetism it can give you lots of
其他物理学，包括超导电荷密度波
other physics as well including
superconductivity charge density waves
还有各种各样的其他事情，这就是为什么有十万
and all sorts of other things which is
why there's been a hundred thousand
用这种哈伯德模型写的论文，你不为我所有的一切负责
papers written on this hubbard model
you're not responsible for all of that i
保证您应该了解流动铁磁性
promise you're supposed to know
something about itinerant ferromagnetism
但是没关系，所以请坐着不动，我们将继续本讲座，因为我们
but that's all okay so sit still we're
gonna go over on this lecture because we
实际上已经结束了课程，所以我只想包装所有内容
actually have come to the end of the
course so I just want to wrap everything
我们要取消明天的讲座这实际上是按计划进行的
up we're gonna cancel tomorrow's lecture
this is this is actually on schedule we
实际上是计划要举行的二十一次讲座，但我会多留一点
is it's actually planned to be twenty
one lectures but I leave an extra
在发生灾难或落后时进行演讲，我们没有落后，我们做了
lecture in case of disasters or running
behind and we didn't run behind we did
一切都按计划进行，因此我们实际上已经完成了该课程，或者
everything exactly as planned so we have
actually finished the course more or
在结束之前，少一些组织评论
less a couple of sort of organizational
comments before before the closing
首先显然没有演讲
remarks
first of all obviously no lecture
明天，这是第一条评论，第二条评论是您知道还是不知道
tomorrow that's the first comment the
second comment is you know one or not
知道一个，但很少有人实际使用此留言板
know one but very few people actually
use the message board heavily this this
这个词没关系，我不知道为什么这是人们不喜欢的，那没关系
term that's okay I don't know why it is
people didn't like it that's that's fine
但您知道此留言板仍在运行，我想随着它的到来
but you know this message board is still
up and running and I think as it gets
靠近考试的人们会更热衷于使用它并询问
closer to exams people will get more
enthusiastic about using it and asking
很好的问题就是要在那里存在，所以不要
questions that's fine that's what it's
meant that to be there for so don't
犹豫使用它向您的心脏的内容提出问题，我将尝试回答
hesitate to use it ask questions to your
heart's content I will try to answer as
当您为考试修改时，我会尽可能多地选择我想要的另一件事
many of them as I can as you revise for
your exams the other thing that I want
问您要做的是让我知道您想要的修订讲座内容
to ask you to do is let me know what you
want to have for the revision lectures
我们必须在三位一体任期的第四周修订讲座，
we have to revision lectures in the
fourth week of Trinity term and I'm
最无聊的事情总是完全不知所措
always completely at a loss as to what
the most useful thing to talk about is
如果您认为我应该尝试给出一个概述，那么您可以
if you think I should try to just give
an overview to do that if you there are
您想从上一年的考试中得到的特定问题
particular questions from that from
previous year's exams that you want to
走过去，让我知道我会尝试组装一些人们会觉得有用的东西
go over let me know I'll try to assemble
something that people will find useful
好了，所以当我们开始的时候，课程的一些总结性想法
alright so just a couple of closing
ideas for the course when we started
七个半星期前，我向我保证，到课程结束时
seven and a half weeks ago I promised
that that by the end of the course we'd
其实对我们周围的世界了解得更多，我认为我们
actually know something more about the
the world around us and I think we
我们真的知道像您这样的事情吗，为什么钻石透明并且
genuinely do we know things like you
know why diamonds transparent and and
为什么要熨磁铁，为什么固体会在较高温度下膨胀，还有很多
why irons a magnet and why solids expand
at higher temperature and and many many
更多的东西，其中有些非常深奥，而有些则不那么深奥
more things and some of them very
esoteric and some of them less esoteric
诸如量子量子效应之类的东西对热很重要
things like quantum
quantum effects are important for heat
容量或晶体管的工作方式，以及如何确定晶体
capacity or how it transistor works and
and how you determine the crystal
我希望为从事科学工作的人们提供X射线材料的结构
structure of a material in x-ray for
those of you who go on in science I hope
这为将来的学习和发现更多内容奠定了良好的基础
this forms a good foundation for for
future learning and discovering more
沿着相同的路线，甚至在其他领域中的事物，
things along the same lines or even in
other fields for those of you don't go
进入科学领域，你知道那也很好，我希望至少是
on into science that's you know that's
fine too I hope that's at least been a
对自然世界的美好而有趣的探索，我希望它能使您离开
good and entertaining exploration of the
natural world and I hope it leaves you
至少我对主题有了更好的理解
with a better appreciation for the
subject at the very least I do realize
本课程内容很多，对此我深表歉意
that there's an awful lot of material in
this course and I apologize about that
考试或多或少地固定了一定数量的材料
it was more or less a fixed amount of
material fixed by the exams the exam
委员会和课程提纲，所以我们实际上没有那么多的自由删除权
committee and the syllabus so we don't
really have that much freedom to remove
因此我意识到很多人认为这是从
material so I realized that a lot of
people view this as drinking from a
你知道，只有这么多的信息才会来袭你
firehose you know it's just so much
information coming you coming at you at
同时很难吸收，但具有讽刺意味的是，最大的问题是
the same time it's hard to absorb but
ironically the the biggest problem with
当然，实际上里面没有足够的东西，我不是说
the course is that there's actually not
enough in it and not I don't say that
因为我觉得您需要为考试学习更多的知识，所以我说是因为
because I feel like you need to learn
more for your exams I say that because
凝聚态物质是一个巨大的主题，以至于我们和我们几乎都没有
condensed matter is such an enormous
subject that it we and we've hardly
划伤表面似乎把它留在这里真可惜，但这就是全部
scratched the surface it seems such a
shame to leave it here but this is all
我们有时间可以轻松地进行为期一年或更长时间的材料讲座
we have time for we could easily do a
year of lectures or more on material
物理或量子效应或统计效应或设备物理或
physics or quantum effects or
statistical effects or device physics or
我们根本没有提到的十几种事物中的任何一种
any one of a dozen types of things that
we just barely mentioned at all and as
以及许多我们甚至没有涉及到的超导体超流体
well as many many things that we didn't
even get to superconductors superfluids
等等，我希望我真的希望你们中的许多人有
fractionalized particles so forth and so
on I hope I really hope many of you have
将来有机会继续学习这些东西的机会
the opportunity to go on and learn about
those things in the future and hopefully
它将会像您学到的一样有趣，甚至更有趣
it will be as entertaining or even more
entertaining as what you've learned so
最后，我只想感谢大家参加讲座和
far finally I just want to thank you all
for having come to lectures and having
整个学期看起来都很热情，非常感谢
looked enthusiastic throughout the term
thank you very much
您
you